

Alessandra Maffei | Frontend Developer

Berlin, Germany +4915236210934 <u>ales.maffei@gmail.com</u> <u>GitHub</u> LinkedIn

Frontend Developer with a 10-year background in digital marketing for international tech companies. Experienced in building web applications using JavaScript, CSS, HTML, and TypeScript. Driven by a passion for technology mixed with the best practices of a (former) marketer: understanding customers and their needs, collaborating across teams towards a business goal, and always learning from every test. Motivated to contribute to Kinsta's mission to create the best hosting platform in the world—to the point of building a web page on the value I'd love to bring to your team.

TECH STACK

HTML5 • CSS3 • JavaScript • TypeScript • ReactJS • Node.js • Express • Bootstrap • TailwindCSS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer (Apprenticeship) - The Collab Lab

MARCH 2023 - NOW

- Collaborate on a remote team of 4 Frontend Developers guided by 2 Senior Engineers
- Build components and features for <u>a Progressive Web App</u> using Semantic HTML, CSS, React, and Google Firestore
- Work in an Agile environment with syncs, retrospectives, and pair programming sessions

Full Stack Web and App Development Graduate - WBS Coding School, Berlin

OCTOBER 2022 - FEBRUARY 2023

- Participated in a full-time practice-oriented coding course (details under "Education")
- Delivered 7 weekly projects (HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Typescript, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap, RESTful APIs, SQL - Postgresql, NoSQL - MongoDB, GIT)

Social & Editorial Lead / Head of Media - CareerFoundry, Berlin

JANUARY 2020 - MARCH 2022

- Led a 12-people remote-first organic marketing team → delivered 40% of monthly revenue
- Managed task planning and established tools/processes for copy, design, and video tickets
- Improved SEO metrics for the <u>CF Blog</u> in collaboration with web developers → Google Speed Performance score increase from 60 to 95 on desktop (primary source)

Head of Social Media - Asana Rebel GmbH, Berlin

JUNE 2019 - JANUARY 2020

Established the social media function (hiring, tooling, processes, campaign planning)

 Acted as the Marketing contact point towards Customer Support and QA Engineering to address product feedback, flag bugs, and submit feature requests

Senior Social Media Manager - <u>Babbel (Lesson Nine GmbH)</u>, Berlin

MAY 2016 - MAY 2019

- Led the global team responsible for Babbel's growth on social media in 7 languages
- Set up the infrastructure for the team to work and collaborate smoothly with Marketing, Customer Support, and Product: tooling, processes, documentation, reporting

(Further professional experiences can be found on LinkedIn)

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web and App Development Program - WBS Coding School

OCTOBER 2022 - FEBRUARY 2023

- Frontend: HTML5 CSS JavaScript (Fundamentals, DOM, Functional Programming, OOP) •
 JavaScript framework: React.js (Fundamentals, UI Components, Hooks, Context) CSS
 preprocessors (SASS) and frameworks (Tailwind CSS)
- Backend: NodeJS/ExpressJS Overview APIs (REST, GraphQL) Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB
- Tools and version control: Console, GIT, and GitHub
- Practices: Pair programming UX/UI Fundamentals Agile Methodologies (SCRUM)

MA Digital Communication - Sapienza Università di Roma

FEB 2009 - FEBRUARY 2011

BA Communication Sciences - Università degli studi Roma TRE

JUNE 2005 - JANUARY 2009

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

- The Weather App | TypeScript, React, TailwindCSS, OpenWeather API
- Ask A Local | React, CSS, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose
- Space Memory Game | React, CSS, Pexel Photo API
- Nonna's Cookbook | React, CSS, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL

TOOLS

- Project-task management | Jira, Asana, Trello
- Collaboration | Miro, Mural, Figma
- Communication and documentation | Confluence, Notion, Loom
- Monitoring and reporting | Google Analytics, Tableau, Hotjar